<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
//
// In order to translate HtmlQ or to customize the texts,
// just change the text between the opening and the closing
// tag. The attribute 'id' is the name of the variable
// and must remain unchanged.
//
// You can use HTML-tags, but you have to braces instead
// of the normal angle brackets, otherwise the import will fail.
// Example: {b}bold{/b}
//
// If your are using German Umlauts and other special
// characters, make sure, that you save this XML-file
// as an UTF-8-document. White-space inbetween the
// nodes are ignored. Any white-space within the text-
// nodes, including leading or trailing whitespace and
// line breaks, is preserved.
//
// ===================================================
//
-->

<language version="1.0" htmlParse="true">

  <!-- misc -->
  <item id="btnContinue">Tiếp tục...</item>
  <item id="btnclose">Đóng</item>
  <item id="btnHelp">Giúp đỡ</item>
  <item id="btnAgreement">Đồng ý</item>
  <item id="btnNeutral">Trung lập</item>
  <item id="btnDisagreement">Không đồng ý</item>
  <item id="btnTransfer">Gửi kết quả</item>
  <item id="btnMail">Gửi kết quả qua email</item>
  <item id="btnPrint">In kết quả</item>
  <item id="btnExit">Thoát</item>
  <item id="selectItem">Xin vui lòng chọn...</item>

  <!-- Warning when user is trying to leave the page (this item was added for HtmlQ) -->
  <item id="leaveSiteWarning">Your answers will be lost.</item>

  <!-- HtmlQ only: In-App Back Button -->
  <item id="backButton">Trở lại</item>
  <item id="fillInRequiredFields">Vui lòng điền hết tất cả thông tin.</item>

  <!-- errors -->
  <item id="errorHead">Error!</item>
  <item id="errorWindowTooSmall">Vui lòng bật full cửa sổ trình duyệt.</item>

  <!-- welcome screen (leave blank to skip screen) -->
  <item id="welcomeHead">Welcome!</item>
  <item id="welcomeText">Please note: This is just a demo and no data will be stored. Thanks to Job van Exel, that we can use his survey as an example.{br}{br}Comments and bug reports are highly welcome.{br}{br}Please click on the continue-button.</item>

  <!-- user login, only displayed if access is restricted (see config-file) -->
  <item id="loginHead">User code</item>
  <item id="loginText">Please enter your user code. Please note, that in this demo any user code will be accepted.{br}{br}{i}Tip: This is an optional step and you can deactivate it in your own survey.{i}</item>
  <item id="loginFormHeader">User code</item>
  <item id="loginNoInput">Please insert your user code.</item>
  <item id="loginInvalidInput">User code invalid</item>
  <item id="loginNoConnection">Connection to server failed. Please try again.</item>

  <!-- introduction (leave blank to skip popup) -->
  <item id="introHead">Giới thiệu</item>
  <item id="introText">This study is about travel behaviour. We are interested in your attitude towards car and public transport as travel alternatives for middle-distance trips.{br}{br}Please maximize your browser window and click on the continue-button to start the survey.</item>

  <!-- step1: rough sorting into three piles (leave blank to skip popup)-->
  <item id="step1Head">Bước 1 trên 5</item>
  <item id="step1Text">Read the folowing statements carefully and split them up into three piles: a pile for statements you tend to disagree with, a pile for cards you tend to agree with, and a pile for the rest.{br}{br}You can either drag the cards into one of the three piles or press 1, 2, 3 on your keyboard. Changes can be made later.{br}{br}If you want to read this instruction a second time, press the help-button at the bottom left corner.{br}{br}Xin vui lòng đọc kĩ các mệnh đề sau đây và xếp chúng vào ba nhóm: nhóm chứa những mệnh đề mà bạn không đồng ý, đồng ý, và một nhóm chứa tất cả những mệnh đề còn lại.{br}{br}Bạn có thể nắm-kéo-thả các thẻ bài/mệnh đề vào một trong ba nhóm bên dưới, hoặc bấm phím 1, 2, 3 trên bàn phím của bạn để phân nhóm chúng. Tất cả mọi lựa chọn đều có thể chỉnh sửa về sau.{br}{br}Nếu bạn muốn đọc hướng dẫn này một lần nữa, nhấn vào nút "Giúp đỡ" ở góc trái bên dưới màn hình.</item>

  <!-- step2: sorting (leave blank to skip popup) -->
  <item id="step2Head">Bước 2 trên 5</item>
  <item id="step2Text">Take the cards from the "AGREE"-pile and read them again. You can scroll through the statements by using the scroll bar. Next, select the two statements you most agree with and place them on right side of the score sheet below the "+2".{br}{br}Now read the cards in the "DISAGREE"-pile again. Just like before, select the two statements you most disagree with and place them on the left side of the score sheet below the "-2".{br}{br}Next, select the statements you second most agree/disagree with and place them under "+1"/"-1". Follow this procedure for all cards in the "AGREE"- and "DIAGREE"-pile.{br}{br}Finally, read the "NEUTRAL"-cards again and arange them in the remaining open boxes of the score sheet.
  {br}{br}{b}HƯỚNG DẪN:{/b}{br}Chọn những thẻ bài mà bạn đã xếp vào nhóm {b}ĐỒNG Ý{/b} và nắm-kéo-thả chúng vào vị trí tương ứng ở tam giác phía trên. Yếu tố ở vị trí "+6" là yếu tố {b}đồng ý nhất{/b}, và bạn chỉ được chọn một thẻ bài cho vị trí này. Tiếp đó xin lựa tiếp hai thẻ cho vị trí "+5", tức là hai yếu tố đồng ý cao, nhưng độ đồng ý nhẹ hơn yếu tố ở vị trí "+6", và tương tự cho các vị trí "+4", "+3",...{br}{br}Bạn hãy làm tương tự như vậy cho các thẻ bài trong nhóm {b}KHÔNG ĐỒNG Ý{/b}. Nắm-kéo-thả yếu tố có {b}không đồng ý nhất{/b} vào vị trí "-6", rồi hai yếu tố không đồng ý tiếp theo vào vị trí "-5",... tiếp tục xếp cho đến khi bạn đã dùng {b}hết{/b} các thẻ bài trong hai nhóm {b}ĐỒNG Ý{/b} và {b}KHÔNG ĐỒNG Ý{/b}.{br}{br}Cuối cùng, bạn hãy xếp các thẻ trong nhóm {b}TRUNG GIAN{/b} vào các vị trí còn lại trong tam giác theo vị trí tương ứng với mức đồng ý/không đồng ý của chúng.{br}{br}Để đọc các thẻ bài trong tam giác, di chuyển và giữ con trỏ chuột ở trên thẻ bài đó.</item>

  <!-- step3: check sorting, only displayed if showStep3== true (see config-file; leave blank to skip popup)-->
  <item id="step3Head">Bước 3 trên 5</item>
  <item id="step3Text">Now you have placed all cards on the score sheet. Please go over your distribution once more and shift cards if you want to.{br}{br}Giờ thì bạn đã xếp các thẻ bài vào vị trí của chúng. Hãy xem qua lại một lần nữa và chỉnh sửa nếu muốn, hoặc tiếp tục tới bước tiếp theo.{br}{br}Để đọc các thẻ bài trong tam giác, di chuyển và giữ con trỏ chuột ở trên thẻ bài đó.</item>

  <!-- step4: comments on best/worst rated statements, only displayed if showStep4== true (see config-file; leave blank to skip popup) -->
  <item id="step4Head">Bước 4 trên 5</item>
  <item id="step4Text">Please explain why you agree most or disagree most with the following statements you have placed below "+2" or "-2".{br}{br}Nếu có thể, xin hãy giải thích vì sao bạn lại xếp hai thẻ bài này vào vị trí dưới mốc "+2" và "-2".</item>

  <!-- step5: dditional questions, only displayed if showStep5== true (see config-file; leave blank to skip popup)-->
  <item id="step5Head">Bước 5 trên 5</item>
  <item id="step5Text">Finally, please answer the following questions regarding your background.{br}{br}Đây là bước cuối cùng. Xin hãy trả lời các câu hỏi sau về bạn.</item>

  <!-- data transfer, only displayed if submitUrl is not blank (see config-file) -->
  <item id="transferHead">Gửi kết quả</item>
  <item id="transferText">Bạn đã hoàn thành khảo sát, xin vui lòng nhấn nút gửi để gửi kết quả đi.</item>
  <item id="transferFailed">Kết quả không gửi được. Xin vui lòng gửi kết quả qua email.</item>
  <item id="transferOk">Thank you for unsing FlashQ. We would appreciate if you could send us feeddback about this application (bugs, ideas, suggestion, etc.).{br}{br}Christian Hackert{br}{a href="http://www.hackert.biz/flashq" target="_blank"}{u}www.hackert.biz/flashq{/u}{/a}.{br}{br}You can now close your browser window.</item>

  <!-- send data via mail, only displayed if submitUrl is blank (see config-file) -->
  <item id="mailHead">Gửi kết quả</item>
  <item id="mailText">You can either submit your data either via email or post. In the former case you'll need an email client like Outlook, in the latter a printer.</item>

  <!-- e-mail-body -->
  <item id="mailBody">Thank you for participating in our survey. Please do not modify the following text:</item>

  <!-- print out -->
  <item id="printoutText">Somebody{br}Some street 100{br}Some city{br}{br}Please send this printout to address mentioned above. Thanks for you help.</item>

</language>