<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-06-11T17:49:15+07:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Duy Dang-Pham</title><subtitle>Duy Dang-Pham (Đặng Phạm Thiên Duy) is an academic at RMIT University. His expertise focuses on information security management and digital transformation.
</subtitle><author><name>Duy Dang-Pham</name></author><entry><title type="html">Full scholarships for PhD research in digital transformation and cybersecurity management areas at RMIT Vietnam</title><link href="/2022/06/11/phd-scholarship-at-rmit-vietnam.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Full scholarships for PhD research in digital transformation and cybersecurity management areas at RMIT Vietnam" /><published>2022-06-11T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2022-06-11T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>/2022/06/11/phd-scholarship-at-rmit-vietnam</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2022/06/11/phd-scholarship-at-rmit-vietnam.html">&lt;p&gt;My research collaborators and I are calling for applications for &lt;strong&gt;five (5) PhD projects&lt;/strong&gt; which will be &lt;strong&gt;fully funded by scholarships&lt;/strong&gt; (covering tuition fee, living stipend, and a USD 3,000 allowance for research activities). Details of the four projects are provided in this post.&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The five projects below can also be found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rmit.edu.au/research/research-degrees/find-a-project&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;this link&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (search for the keyword “RMIT Vietnam”)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Candidates wishing to apply for a Higher Degree by Research will need to provide a research proposal which is aligned to your chosen research project.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check your egibility for PhD programs at RMIT University:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rmit.edu.vn/study-at-rmit/phd-programs/phd-apply&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.rmit.edu.vn/study-at-rmit/phd-programs/phd-apply&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To discuss the PhD scholarship opportunities, please send me an email at: &lt;strong&gt;duy.dangphamthien {at} rmit.edu.vn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 style=&quot;font-size: 150%; color: Brown; font-weight: bold&quot;&gt;Digital transformation and digitalisation of healthcare in Vietnam&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital transformation and the digitalisation of processes, which leverage digital technologies to optimise existing operations and create improvements, have been rapidly taking place in organisations of all sizes and across different sectors. As the COVID-19 pandemic continues to impact societies around the world, the healthcare sector is put under pressure to adopt digital technologies to ensure healthy lives and promote wellbeing for citizens of all ages. Nevertheless, the extant literature has shown that digital transformation programs are often large and complex, and contextual i.e., there is no one-size-fits-all solution for digital transformation across different contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doctoral research project will employ a mixed method approach to examine the success factors and challenges in the adoption of digital technologies from both the perspectives of healthcare centres (e.g., hospitals and clinics) and relevant stakeholders (e.g., doctors, nurses, professional staff, as well as patients and policy makers). Furthermore, it involves developing and delivering a comprehensive training program to enhance digital transformation capabilities of healthcare centres and staff in Vietnam. The project will put forward a validated framework that outlines the best practices for digital transformation and digitalisation in the healthcare context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PhD candidate(s) working on this project will be mentored by experienced and senior researchers who have established research track records in the digital transformation and digitalisation areas. The candidate(s) will also have access to networks of researchers in the Managing Smart Transformation research cluster at RMIT Vietnam and RMIT Australia, as well as healthcare centres and medical professionals in Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicants for this project will be based on the RMIT Vietnam campus, but will be enrolled through RMIT Australia as offshore candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;College:&lt;/strong&gt; Business and Law&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;School:&lt;/strong&gt; Graduate School of Business and Law&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Discipline:&lt;/strong&gt; Business&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Program Code:&lt;/strong&gt; DR205&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Campus:&lt;/strong&gt; RMIT Vietnam&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enabling Capability Platform:&lt;/strong&gt; GBI 2 Organizational Transformation and Innovation Capabilities Enhancement; SC 1 Transformations in health and social policy and practice;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;FoR Code(s):&lt;/strong&gt; 350303 Business information systems (50%) 350304 Business systems in context (25%) 350307 Technology management (25%)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 style=&quot;font-size: 150%; color: Brown; font-weight: bold&quot;&gt;Success factors and challenges of algorithmic decision-making in healthcare&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As data-driven technologies are widely adopted in different settings, scholars and practitioners have recently studied aspects of algorithmic decision-making (ADM), or the process where decisions are made either directly by the algorithms or by a human decision-maker supported by algorithms. In either case, many concerns have been raised regarding the fairness, transparency, accuracy, accountability, data privacy, and security of ADM, to name a few. More importantly, these concerns need to be addressed when ADM is applied in critical contexts such as healthcare. This doctoral research project will employ a mixed-methods approach to explore the success factors and challenges associated with the existing or potential use of ADM in healthcare from the perspective of users. The project would contribute practical implications for designing ADM process and data-driven healthcare technologies that are both useful and acceptable to societies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicants for this project will be based on the RMIT Vietnam campus, but will be enrolled through RMIT Australia as offshore candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;College:&lt;/strong&gt; Business and Law&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;School:&lt;/strong&gt; Graduate School of Business and Law&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Discipline:&lt;/strong&gt; Business&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Program Code:&lt;/strong&gt; DR205&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Campus:&lt;/strong&gt; RMIT Vietnam&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enabling Capability Platform:&lt;/strong&gt; GBI 2 Organizational Transformation and Innovation Capabilities Enhancement; SC 1 Transformations in health and social policy and practice&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;FoR Code(s):&lt;/strong&gt; 350303 Business information systems (50%) 350304 Business systems in context (25%) 350307 Technology management (25%)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 style=&quot;font-size: 150%; color: Brown; font-weight: bold&quot;&gt;Moving toward an inclusive and sustainable digital nation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vietnam has set an ambitious goal - moving toward a digital nation by 2030. The National Programme for Digital Transformation aims to “develop a digital government, digital economy, and digital society and to establish Vietnamese digital technology enterprises capable of going global” (Prime Minister of Vietnam, 2020). Although the country has taken great initiatives to excel through smart cities and industry 4.0, the actual implementation shows there were still many difficulties and challenges for city leaders, management agencies, and businesses.
Potential topic(s) explore the inclusive and sustainable digital transformation of Vietnam, e.g., digital government, digital society, digital economy, international business, and benchmarking of smart and sustainable cities. These projects aim to examine drivers, barriers, and government’s support for an inclusive and sustainable digital nation; to recast the new globalization and define the new meaning of ‘born global’; or to benchmark smart city. The Ph.D. candidate(s) working on this project will be mentored by experienced researchers in the e-government and digitalization areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicants for this project will be based on the RMIT Vietnam campus, but will be enrolled through RMIT Australia as offshore candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;College:&lt;/strong&gt; Business and Law&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;School:&lt;/strong&gt; Graduate School of Business and Law&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Discipline:&lt;/strong&gt; Business&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Program Code:&lt;/strong&gt; DR205&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Campus:&lt;/strong&gt; RMIT Vietnam&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enabling Capability Platform:&lt;/strong&gt; GBI 2 Organizational Transformation and Innovation Capabilities Enhancement;SC 3 Transformations in digital society and economy;UF 2 Smart cities analytics;GBI 3 Innovation Governance and Performance&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;FoR Code(s):&lt;/strong&gt; 350714 Public sector organisation and management (50%) 350706 International business (25%) 350307 Technology management (25%)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 style=&quot;font-size: 150%; color: Brown; font-weight: bold&quot;&gt;Exploring user security behaviour in WFH context&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many organizations around the globe have let their employees work from home, especially due to the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic, which expose these organizations to various information security risks in the employees’ work environment at home. While prior research has examined the cognitive factors that influenced the information security behaviors of remote workers, little was known about the impact of the different work environments on these behaviors. Moreover, organizations and employees are abruptly forced to embrace working from home, which create unprecedented problems and inconvenience in how employees perform daily work at home that could jeopardize organizational information security. This project proposes to adapt the Technology-Organization-Environment (TOE) framework to investigate the factors that influence how employees protect organizational information security while working from home during an extended period. In terms of theoretical implications, the project focuses on exploring the contextual and situational factors that influence employee information security behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicants for this project will be based on the RMIT Vietnam campus, but will be enrolled through RMIT Australia as offshore candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;College:&lt;/strong&gt; Business and Law&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;School:&lt;/strong&gt; Accounting, Information Systems and Supply Chain&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Discipline:&lt;/strong&gt; Information and Communications Technology (ICT)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Program Code:&lt;/strong&gt; DR201&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Campus:&lt;/strong&gt; RMIT Vietnam&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enabling Capability Platform:&lt;/strong&gt; ISE 4 Cyber Security&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;FoR Code(s):&lt;/strong&gt; 460499 Cybersecurity and privacy not elsewhere classified (25%) 460904 Information security management (75%)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 style=&quot;font-size: 150%; color: Brown; font-weight: bold&quot;&gt;Social marketing approach in encouraging employee security compliance&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the behavioral change process of system users to adopt safe security practices is important to the success of an organization’s cybersecurity program. Internal marketing is an effective strategy to enhance organizational capabilities and competencies, by influencing employees’ attitudes and behaviors towards organizational goals. Social marketing adopts the concepts and techniques of commercial marketing to influence target audiences to adopt or sustain behavior in pursuit of social goals such as in increasing pro-environmental behavior, health related behavior, and service quality. Internal social marketing (ISM) combines social and internal marketing, applying internal marketing to influence employees’ attitude and behavior towards organizational changes, but to aiming to achieve social, rather than commercial objectives. This study aims to apply 7Ps marketing mix, as part of an ISM approach, and measure its effectiveness on employee compliance behaviour. This understanding could inform the design of behavioral infrastructure to promote and maintain cybersecurity compliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicants for this project will be based on the RMIT Vietnam campus, but will be enrolled through RMIT Australia as offshore candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;College:&lt;/strong&gt; Business and Law&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;School:&lt;/strong&gt; Business and Management VN&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Discipline:&lt;/strong&gt; Information and Communications Technology (ICT)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Program Code:&lt;/strong&gt; DR201&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Campus:&lt;/strong&gt; RMIT Vietnam&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enabling Capability Platform:&lt;/strong&gt; ISE 4 Cyber Security&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;FoR Code(s):&lt;/strong&gt; 460904 Information security management (60%) 350612 Social marketing (30% 350604 Marketing communications (10%)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>[&quot;Duy Dang-Pham&quot;]</name></author><summary type="html">My research collaborators and I are calling for applications for five (5) PhD projects which will be fully funded by scholarships (covering tuition fee, living stipend, and a USD 3,000 allowance for research activities). Details of the four projects are provided in this post.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/img/2022_06/phd.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/img/2022_06/phd.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">VET training on Artificial Intelligence and Data Science for Digital Transformation</title><link href="/2022/05/31/vet-training-on-ai-and-ds-for-digital-transformation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="VET training on Artificial Intelligence and Data Science for Digital Transformation" /><published>2022-05-31T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2022-05-31T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>/2022/05/31/vet-training-on-ai-and-ds-for-digital-transformation</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2022/05/31/vet-training-on-ai-and-ds-for-digital-transformation.html">&lt;p&gt;I felt great to be part of the RMIT Vietnam expert delivery team, consisting of 10 academic staff, and together we conducted an intensive, one-week executive training for Vietnamese Education officers and their Logistics partners, commissioned by Aus4Skills (through Dr. Kaye Eldridge).&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The training for Leading in the Age of Digital Disruption Vocational Education Training, was launched at RMIT Vietnam by the Australian Consul General. The training supports the College of Business and Law RMIT D3 strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My session on AI, Machine Learning and Data Science for Digital Transformation was well received by the participants, as shown in the post-training evaluation survey. 
I was also glad to attend the presentations by the participants as a judge. The participants understood well the important use of AI, Machine Learning and Data Science for their digital transformation, and they proposed innovative plans to implement these technologies to meet their organisation’s strategic goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/vet_training_june22_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dr Duy Dang-Pham conducting VET training&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; style=&quot;display:block; margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Dr Duy Dang-Pham conducting VET training&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/vet_training_june22_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Presentation session with the training participants&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; style=&quot;display:block; margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Presentation session with the training participants&lt;/figcaption&gt;</content><author><name>[&quot;Duy Dang-Pham&quot;]</name></author><summary type="html">I felt great to be part of the RMIT Vietnam expert delivery team, consisting of 10 academic staff, and together we conducted an intensive, one-week executive training for Vietnamese Education officers and their Logistics partners, commissioned by Aus4Skills (through Dr. Kaye Eldridge).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/img/vet_training_june22_1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/img/vet_training_june22_1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Chuyển đổi số và nghịch lý</title><link href="/2022/02/23/chuyen-doi-so-va-nghich-ly.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chuyển đổi số và nghịch lý" /><published>2022-02-23T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2022-02-23T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>/2022/02/23/chuyen-doi-so-va-nghich-ly</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2022/02/23/chuyen-doi-so-va-nghich-ly.html">&lt;p&gt;Một câu hỏi mà cho đến nay vẫn chưa có kết luận cuối cùng: “Chuyển đổi số (digital transformation) khác với triển khai IT (IT implementation) như thế nào?” Bên cạnh các câu trả lời được đồng ý rộng rãi, còn một vấn đề thú vị mà lại nhận được ít thảo luận hơn - sự nghịch lý (paradox) trong chuyển đổi số.&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt; Về bản thân, khái niệm nghịch lý và nghiên cứu học thuật về mối quan hệ giữa nghịch lý và sự liên kết chiến lược (strategic alignment) của CNTT trong tổ chức đã có từ lâu, với lý thuyết nghịch lý (paradox theory) cung cấp một nền tảng cơ bản cho các phân tích sâu hơn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;định-nghĩa-và-bản-chất-của-nghịch-lý&quot;&gt;Định nghĩa và bản chất của nghịch lý&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/paradox.jpg&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin-right:40px; margin-bottom:20px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theo lý thuyết nghịch lý, nghịch lý được định nghĩa là bao gồm “những yếu tố mâu thuẫn nhưng có liên quan lẫn nhau, tồn tại song song và trường tồn theo thời gian.” (“contradictory yet interrelated elements that exist simultaneously and persis over time.”) Bản chất của nghịch lý trong bối cảnh của tổ chức (organization) là tension (sự căng thẳng), và có một số khái niệm giống và liên quan tới nghịch lý bao gồm dilemma (song đề, bao gồm những tension mang tính chất “either-or” hay sự tồn tại của hai lựa chọn có lợi-hại rõ ràng), trade-off (thỏa hiệp, bao gồm sự cân nhắc các lựa chọn trên một thang điểm có hai cực trái ngược), dialectic (biện chứng, bao gồm các luận đề và phản đề đại diện cho các phương án dẫn đến sự đối lập mà cần được xử lý bằng sự hợp thành/integration), và duality (tính hai mặt, bao gồm các yêu cầu cạnh tranh/competing và bổ trợ/complementary lẫn nhau). Lý thuyết nghịch lý ủng hộ lối suy nghĩ “both-and”, khi các nhà quản lý công nhận và đối diện với toàn bộ các yếu tố mâu thuẫn và sự căng thẳng tồn tại song song, thay vì đưa ra lựa chọn giữa chúng. Cách tiếp cận này cũng là nền tảng của các phương án xử lý vấn đề mang tính sáng tạo (creative) và có giá trị lâu dài (sustainable/long-term).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cũng theo lý thuyết nghịch lý, các nghịch lý luôn luôn tồn tại trong các tổ chức - dù chúng có nằm ẩn (latent) hay bị cố tình né tránh suốt một thời gian và trở thành tâm điểm quan trọng (salient) của một tổ chức khi có tác nhân (trigger) kích hoạt. Chính vì vậy, chuyển đổi số &lt;em&gt;không tạo ra nghịch lý từ con số 0&lt;/em&gt;, mà chỉ làm cho các nghịch lý tiềm ẩn trở nên rõ ràng hơn trong tổ chức. Tác nhân dẫn đến nghịch lý, hay nói chính xác hơn là các tension (sự căng thẳng, bao gồm các yêu cầu cạnh tranh/competing demands), nằm trong thực tại phức tạp (complex reality) của tổ chức. Thực tại phức tạp này bao gồm ba yếu tố chính: plurality (tính đa số trong quan điểm, chiến lược, những thành viên trong tổ chức), scarcity (tính khan hiếm của tài nguyên tổ chức như thời gian, tài năng, hay tiền bạc), và change (tính thay đổi). Có thể thấy rằng quá trình chuyển đổi số khi diễn ra luôn có ba yếu tố này khi tổ chức muốn áp dụng công nghệ mới nhằm tạo ra các thay đổi lớn liên quan đến quy trình làm việc, mô hình kinh doanh, hay danh tính (identity) của tổ chức (ví dụ: một công ty B2B muốn áp dụng công nghệ nền tảng (platform) và chiến lược marketing số để nhắm đến thị trường B2C; quyết định thay đổi này xuất phát từ các thay đổi trong thị trường về mặt khách hàng cũng như đối thủ cạnh tranh; từ khâu lên kế hoạch cho đến thực hiện thay đổi sẽ khiến ban quản lý phải cân nhắc các thiết kế giải pháp và chiến lược kinh doanh khác nhau, đôi khi bao gồm việc lựa chọn nên giữ lại hay bỏ đi những cái cũ để tiến về phía trước, cũng như là sự giới hạn của tiền cũng như nhân lực với kĩ năng mới mà tổ chức chưa có).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zFAlWgaR2i0&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nghịch lý có thể xuất hiện dưới nhiều dạng và ở các cấp độ khác nhau trong bối cảnh tổ chức, bao gồm cấp độ cá nhân, dự án, doanh nghiệp, và mạng lưới. Có nhiều dạng nghịch lý khác nhau để mô tả các nhu cầu cạnh tranh, ví dụ như quản lý chiến lược-sáng kiến, đầu tư công nghệ-hiệu suất, hay nghịch lý của sự thành công (khi doanh nghiệp càng thành công thì càng dễ có khả năng bị lệ thuộc vào các phương pháp cũ dẫn đến kém thành công hơn trong tương lai dài), và lý thuyết nghịch lý chỉ ra bốn loại nghịch lý chính: 1) belonging (sự thuộc về), 2) learning (học tập), 3) organizing (tổ chức), và 4) performing (thi hành). Nghịch lý belonging tồn tại với các giá trị cốt lõi và vai trò mang tính đối kháng nhau trong tổ chức (vd: một doanh nghiệp truyền thống tái định hình lại danh tính của mình như một doanh nghiệp số). Nghịch lý learning nói đến sự đối chọi giữa cái cũ và cái mới trong quy trình làm việc hay năng lực cốt lõi của tổ chức khi các ý tưởng mới được đưa ra và triển khai, khiến kiềm hãm sự phát triển của tổ chức. Nghịch lý organizing bao gồm sự phân bổ tài nguyên và các kiến trúc tổ chức khách nhau cho các nhu cầu cạnh tranh, và nghịch lý performing nói đến các mục tiêu và mối quan tâm đối kháng với nhau của các thành viên trong tổ chức. Bốn loại nghịch lý này được cho rằng sẽ tồn tại rõ rệt nhất ở cấp độ mạng lưới các tổ chức hoặc đối với từng doanh nghiệp, và khi xuống các cấp độ chi tiết hơn như dự án hay cá nhân thành viên tổ chức, các loại nghịch lý trở nên phức tạp hơn dưới các dạng kết hợp như belonging-learning, learning-organizing, hay organizing-performing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quản-lý-nghịch-lý-trong-chuyển-đổi-số&quot;&gt;Quản lý nghịch lý trong chuyển đổi số&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vậy nhà quản lý sẽ làm gì với các nghịch lý trong tổ chức và trong quá trình chuyển đổi số?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Như đã nhắc đến ở trên, lý thuyết nghịch lý khuyến khích các phương án mang tính “both-and” hướng đến việc xử lý tất cả các nhu cầu và yếu tố cạnh tranh thay vì lựa chọn giữa chúng. Lý thuyết nghịch lý xem lối suy nghĩ “both-and” này thuộc nhóm active (chủ động), bao gồm các hướng tiếp cận cụ thể hơn như acceptance (chấp nhận), confrontation (đối đầu), và transcendence (vượt qua). Nhóm phương án chủ động này bao gồm tự nguyện chấp nhận sự cần thiết của nỗ lực nhằm cân bằng các yếu tố trái cực nhau dẫn đến tension (sự căng thẳng), trực tiếp làm việc với các nguyên nhân dẫn đến tension (vd: có thể nhờ một bên thứ ba để can thiệp và quản lý các phản ứng từ nhiều phía các nhau), và nhìn thấu đáo được những yếu tố nghịch lý nào nên xem là phụ thuộc lẫn nhau (complex interdependencies) hay lợi ích cạnh tranh (competing interests).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Một số ví dụ của phương án chủ động trong chuyển đổi số để xử lý nghịch lý bao gồm thiết kế một nền tảng IT cốt lõi với các components rời có thể thay đổi được mà không làm ảnh hưởng tới nền tảng lõi, hay ngân hàng DBS Bank đã kết hợp nhân sự các phòng ban riêng rẽ để tạo thành bộ phận Group Technology and Operations, bao gồm project managers, business analysts và system analysts để chủ động tạo giá trị cho công nghệ của họ. Trong bài &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-030-80003-1_18&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;nghiên cứu gần đây về phương pháp Digital Kaizen của FPT Software&lt;/a&gt;, tổ chức này đã thực hiện các workshop để các phòng ban và bộ phận có thể thảo luận, phát hiện và đánh giá các cross-functional pain points của nhau và từ đó dẫn đến các sáng kiến chuyển đổi số - đây cũng có thể được xem là một phương án xử lý nghịch lý mang tính chủ động.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trái với nhóm giải pháp chủ động có tác dụng xử lý nghịch lý về mặt lâu dài, nhóm giải pháp defensive (phòng thủ) có thể tạm xử lý nghịch lý trong thời gian ngắn hơn nhưng lại kém hiệu quả trong việc nâng cao hiểu biết về bản chất của nghịch lý, cũng như đưa ra được những cách làm việc mới với nghịch lý. Nhóm defensive này bao gồm các phương án như splitting (tách rời), regression (hồi quy), repression (đàn áp), projection (trù hoạch), reaction formation (hình thành phản ứng), hay ambivalence (mơ hồ). Ví dụ như việc hình thành một team chuyển đổi số làm việc độc lập với bộ phận IT được xem như là phương pháp splitting, hay việc các quản lý tầm trung với kiến thức sâu về sản xuất film trong case study nổi tiếng Kodak đã từ chối các ý tưởng và tài nguyên để làm sản phẩm số (digital products) là một ví dụ của sử dụng phương pháp repression trong xử lý nghịch lý.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lý thuyết nghịch lý và nghịch lý là một đề tài nghiên cứu học thuật mới nổi và lý thú trong lĩnh vực chuyển đổi số, và nhóm của tôi tại Đại học RMIT đang có một số đề tài và dự án nghiên cứu liên quan đến chủ đề này, hiện đang mong muốn được hợp tác với các doanh nghiệp đã, đang và sẽ tiến hành chuyển đổi số, đặc biệt ở Việt Nam. Sinh viên, nghiên cứu sinh Tiến sỹ (PhD) có định hướng nghiên cứu về chủ đề này tại RMIT cũng có thể liên hệ với tôi qua địa chỉ email duy.dangphamthien {at} rmit.edu.vn để tìm hiểu về học bổng Tiến sỹ hoặc cơ hội làm Trợ lý nghiên cứu (Research Assistant) hoặc Nghiên cứu viên (Research Fellow).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>[&quot;Duy Dang-Pham&quot;]</name></author><summary type="html">Một câu hỏi mà cho đến nay vẫn chưa có kết luận cuối cùng: “Chuyển đổi số (digital transformation) khác với triển khai IT (IT implementation) như thế nào?” Bên cạnh các câu trả lời được đồng ý rộng rãi, còn một vấn đề thú vị mà lại nhận được ít thảo luận hơn - sự nghịch lý (paradox) trong chuyển đổi số.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/img/paradox.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/img/paradox.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Chia sẻ mùa lễ cuối năm 2021</title><link href="/2021/12/24/chia-se-mua-le-cuoi-nam-2021.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chia sẻ mùa lễ cuối năm 2021" /><published>2021-12-24T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2021-12-24T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>/2021/12/24/chia-se-mua-le-cuoi-nam-2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/12/24/chia-se-mua-le-cuoi-nam-2021.html">&lt;p&gt;Sau 6 tháng “từ quan” làm Senior Program Manager/SPM (mà tôi hay gọi đùa là “Siêu Phô Mai”) ở khoa cũ, thì bắt đầu từ 1.1.2022 tôi sẽ trở lại với một vị trí SPM khác ở khoa hiện tại. Theo mô tả công việc của vị trí này, tôi sẽ quản lý các vấn đề liên quan đến các chương trình đào tạo Tiến sỹ (PhD) ở trường tôi, bao gồm hỗ trợ nghiên cứu sinh PhD và giáo sư hướng dẫn, cũng như đóng góp ý kiến trực tiếp vào đường hướng và chiến lược nghiên cứu của khoa. Đây cũng là vị trí management/leadership thứ hai của tôi, kể từ khi tôi bắt đầu sự nghiệp academic của mình từ 3 năm trước.&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Càng say yes với các cơ hội mới, tiếp xúc với nhiều người hơn và xử lý các vấn đề mới, và hơn hết là có những lúc đi chậm lại để có một khoảng tĩnh mà xâu chuỗi các thông tin lại với nhau, tôi mới càng cảm nhận rõ hơn “biển học là bao la”. Tôi trở nên “lười nói lười viết” trên mạng, một phần nhỏ do mình tự hỏi mục đích của nói và viết là gì, một phần lớn hơn là tự thấy chẳng có gì sâu sắc để truyền đạt. Tôi có phần khâm phục những người có nhiều đóng góp trên mạng xã hội khi đăng những bài bình luận dài và có tính thông tin cao, và cũng tự nhủ trong lòng phải phấn đấu viết nhiều hơn trong tương lai, có lẽ xuất phát từ chuyện dịch và đăng dần các bài xuất bản nghiên cứu về bảo mật thông tin hay chuyển đổi số của mình. Đây có thể là một trong những New Year resolution cho 2022?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hai cuộc phỏng vấn cho hai vị trí SPM cho tôi cơ hội để chiêm nghiệm thêm về sự thay đổi của bản thân. Buổi phỏng vấn cho vị trí thứ nhất xoáy vào các câu hỏi nhằm để hiểu được tôi “quan tâm” tới ngành và khoa của mình tới đâu, và cô Trưởng khoa cũng muốn biết tôi có những hoài bão gì cho khoa. Buổi phỏng vấn cho vị trí thứ hai thì khác một chút, với nhiều câu hỏi tình huống hơn về cách tôi xử lý các vấn đề giữa người và người (“ngoại giao”) như thế nào. Trong buổi phỏng vấn thứ hai, có một lần tôi thành thật chia sẻ với hội đồng: “nhìn này, có một sự thật là mọi vấn đề luôn luôn có giải pháp, và mối quan tâm chính của tôi không phải là xử lý vấn đề bằng cách nào, mà chúng ta muốn vấn đề được xử lý như thế nào.” Lúc ấy tôi vô thức nói ra câu đấy như thể nó đã luôn nằm sẵn trong đầu tôi, và ngay sau đó khi nghĩ lại, đó chẳng phải là một điều gì cao siêu, vì tôi cam đoan chắc rằng ai cũng có thể hiểu cái lẽ ấy, nhưng để vô thức nói ra điều đó thì trong tôi đã thay đổi. Từ lúc nào đó, tôi đã ngừng dành quá nhiều thời gian suy nghĩ về phương pháp giải quyết vấn đề, mà suy nghĩ nhiều hơn về cách thức vấn đề đó được xử lý. Tôi cảm thấy mình hơi ngạo mạn và có sự tự tin không hề nhẹ khi nói ra điều này.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/art-of-war-xmas-2021.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Art of War&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin-right:40px; margin-bottom:20px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trong suốt gần nửa năm cả thành phố lockdown, tôi chạy trên máy chạy bộ. Tôi duy trì chuyện chạy máy như một thói quen, bắt đầu từ 20 phút một ngày, lên 45 phút một ngày để hoàn thành 4km, lên 35 phút một ngày, và hiện tại là 30 phút một ngày để hoàn thành 6km, kèm thêm 15 phút tập tạ tay. Kết quả là tôi giảm 9kg sau 6 tháng. Bạn bè hỏi tôi lấy động lực gì để bỗng dưng duy trì việc chạy, tôi chưa trả lời ai nghiêm túc bao giờ - mình thích thì mình làm thôi. Tôi đã đọc cuốn “Tôi nói gì khi tôi nói về chạy bộ” của tác giả Murakami, một phần của lí do là tôi muốn cải thiện khả năng tập trung và duy trì thói quen tốt của bản thân, đặc biệt khi sống trong thời đại 4.0 này. Qua bài viết này thì tôi cũng trả lời thật, lí do chính là vì tôi lo cho sức khỏe, hay nói huỵch toẹt ra là tôi sợ chết. Tôi thừa cân và duy trì thể trạng đó trong mùa Covid không phải là điều nên làm. Thế nên nhìn lại câu cuối của đoạn trên thì đừng hiểu lầm, tôi không dám ngạo mạn đâu - ngược lại là đằng khác, tôi “nhát” lắm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ngoài sách của Murakami, tôi cũng đọc đi đọc lại “Binh pháp Tôn Tử” - quyển sách bé tí của nhà xuất bản Penguin mà tôi mua lúc đợi máy bay ở Melbourne đó mà. Tôi thấy thú vị khi nghĩ đến bối cảnh 2500 trước đã có một người như Tôn Tử dành thời gian để hệ thống hóa kinh nghiệm và kiến thức chiến tranh lại thành một cuốn playbook cho cả tướng quân và vương chủ. Tôi đồng cảm được với quyển sách và tác giả, khi trong giai đoạn này của sự nghiệp tôi cũng đang dành thời gian nghiên cứu cuốn playbook cho riêng mình. Nhưng mà trong 3 năm gần đây, tôi có làm vài chuyện khá “điên”, trái với sự “nhát” của mình. Là một con người bình thường hoạt động với lý trí có giới hạn, tôi cũng thường hay trở nên phi lý trí.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lan man viết vài dòng chia sẻ về bản thân, về những gì đã thay đổi và những gì vẫn được giữ lại và “củng cố”, xin cảm ơn sự quan tâm của bạn. Chúc bạn và gia đình một mùa lễ hạnh phúc và mọi điều tốt đẹp nhất cho năm 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>[&quot;Duy Dang-Pham&quot;]</name></author><summary type="html">Sau 6 tháng “từ quan” làm Senior Program Manager/SPM (mà tôi hay gọi đùa là “Siêu Phô Mai”) ở khoa cũ, thì bắt đầu từ 1.1.2022 tôi sẽ trở lại với một vị trí SPM khác ở khoa hiện tại. Theo mô tả công việc của vị trí này, tôi sẽ quản lý các vấn đề liên quan đến các chương trình đào tạo Tiến sỹ (PhD) ở trường tôi, bao gồm hỗ trợ nghiên cứu sinh PhD và giáo sư hướng dẫn, cũng như đóng góp ý kiến trực tiếp vào đường hướng và chiến lược nghiên cứu của khoa. Đây cũng là vị trí management/leadership thứ hai của tôi, kể từ khi tôi bắt đầu sự nghiệp academic của mình từ 3 năm trước.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/img/art-of-war-xmas-2021.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/img/art-of-war-xmas-2021.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">New book chapter about Digital Kaizen at FPT</title><link href="/2021/11/08/new-digital-kaizen-book-chapter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New book chapter about Digital Kaizen at FPT" /><published>2021-11-08T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2021-11-08T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>/2021/11/08/new-digital-kaizen-book-chapter</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/11/08/new-digital-kaizen-book-chapter.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m glad to find that our book chapter about the novel Digital Kaizen methodology for implementing digital transformation has been published in the book &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/book/10.1007/978-3-030-80003-1&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;Digitalization Cases Volume 2&lt;/a&gt;. In this chapter, we explore the applications of the Digital Kaizen methodology in guiding FPT’s digital transformation journey and in helping them to commercialize their digital transformation solutions.&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our appreciation goes to FPT Software for providing the opportunity to publish this case study, and especially Quang Tran for working together with us on this chapter as a co-author. I would also like to thank my research collaborators at RMIT, Ai-Phuong Hoang and Diem-Trang Vo, as well as the Editorial Members of the book who gave us constructive feedback to finish the chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book chapter can be viewed &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-030-80003-1_18&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;here in this link&lt;/a&gt;. I would also recommend readers to read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/book/10.1007/978-3-030-80003-1&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;full book&lt;/a&gt; which comprises 21 case studies detailing the latest and practical digital transformation efforts that took place around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We actively conduct research on digital transformation topics at RMIT Vietnam, and we would love to collaborate with companies to write insightful case studies about these topics. Please don’t hesitate to reach out to us and we can work on exciting digital transformation research together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract-of-the-book-chapter&quot;&gt;Abstract of the book chapter:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a) Situation faced:&lt;/strong&gt; While companies are leveraging technologies to improve their business performance, digital transformation is still perceived as an abstract concept. Most companies do not know where and how to start. FPT Software’s lack of synergy prevents the company from reaping the benefits of its digital transformation activities. The large-scale transformation also requires a ready-to-change culture, which can be daunting to a company with more than 28,000 employees across geographies with different technological capabilities. This chapter explores the applications of Digital Kaizen methodology in guiding FPT Software’s digital transformation journey and in helping them to commercialize their digital transformation solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(b) Action taken:&lt;/strong&gt; FPT Software tackles cross-functional pain points by implementing technological initiatives that improve business processes and increase employee engagement. These initiatives are well aligned with the company’s strategic goals; thus, they are sustainable and scalable digital transformation solutions. First, cross-functional pain points are identified by both managers and working-level employees through conducting workshops. Second, a series of manageable digital transformations are performed to change business processes, the employees’ mindsets, and work processes. Last, FPT Software commercializes its own successful digital transformation initiatives and sell them as solutions to the clients. Two digital transformation projects, MyFPT and AkaLink, are presented in this chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(c) Results achieved:&lt;/strong&gt; The Digital Kaizen methodology has urged FPT Software to continuously optimize and improve their business operations through implementing innovative transformations. By implementing incremental improvements, MyFPT has resolved 22 strategic pain points until June 2020. AkaLink has addressed 19 pain points, resulting in approximately USD700,000 in terms of monetary benefits. It is projected to rise to USD2.5 million after 1 year. These digital transformation projects also produced spillover effects, i.e., driving people engagement and nurturing the culture of change, which benefit the whole company. FPT Software commercializes its digital transformation solutions by using successful projects as practical case studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(d) Lessons learned:&lt;/strong&gt; FPT Software’s digital transformation journey offers three main lessons. First, driving digital transformation through making incremental changes enables companies to realize the benefits quickly. This subsequently motivates transformation activities at large scale across the entire organization. By selecting the cross-functional pain points that are aligned with strategic objectives, FPT Software has solved operational issues without losing sight of its long-term vision. Second, companies should improve organizational change capacity by engaging their own employees who are the drivers of digital transformations. Third, as digital transformation is an ongoing process, a philosophy-driven digital transformation, such as that guided by Digital Kaizen, would develop a climate of engagement and creativity among organizational members at all levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/digital-kaizen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Digital Kaizen at FPT&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Image source: https://blog.fpt-software.com/digital-kaizen-an-approach-for-large-scale-digital-transformation&lt;/figcaption&gt;</content><author><name>[&quot;Duy Dang-Pham&quot;]</name></author><summary type="html">I’m glad to find that our book chapter about the novel Digital Kaizen methodology for implementing digital transformation has been published in the book Digitalization Cases Volume 2. In this chapter, we explore the applications of the Digital Kaizen methodology in guiding FPT’s digital transformation journey and in helping them to commercialize their digital transformation solutions.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/img/digital-kaizen.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/img/digital-kaizen.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Some notes on research collaboration</title><link href="/2021/10/15/some-notes-on-research-collaboration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some notes on research collaboration" /><published>2021-10-15T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2021-10-15T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>/2021/10/15/some-notes-on-research-collaboration</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/10/15/some-notes-on-research-collaboration.html">&lt;p&gt;Some personal notes on getting involved in multi-disciplinary research collaboration.&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Elsevier-collab-image.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;research collaboration&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Image source: https://www.elsevier.com/connect/a-brief-guide-to-research-collaboration-for-the-young-scholar&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-what-benefits-do-i-get-from-research-collaboration&quot;&gt;1. What benefits do I get from research collaboration?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier, getting involved in a research collaboration offers a range of benefits. First, depending on how the tasks are managed, research collaboration would be one of the fastest ways to produce a publication. I have been involved in some collaborations where a team of three people were able to finish writing up a journal manuscript in a week (and eventually got it accepted for publication). However, it should be emphasize that outputs should not be the only expectation from a research collaboration. Gaining new knowledge and experiences, stepping into a new field or area of research, and more importantly, expanding your research network, are all important reasons for getting involved in a collaborative project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-should-i-get-involved-in-a-project-in-a-different-field-or-area-of-research&quot;&gt;2. Should I get involved in a project in a different field or area of research?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It depends. You can expect to get some of the benefits of research collaboration even when you work on a research topic that is completely unrelated to yours. For instance, my background is in information systems (or more specifically, information security management and digital transformation), but I was involved in more than one research projects about designing and developing artificial intelligence-enabled technologies in healthcare (which belong more to the computer science discipline). It’s not a complete disconnection between my information systems background and the AI-enabled health tech area (what would be a mismatch is me getting involved in an art or archaeology research project, but hey, deep learning is being used to generate paintings and music nowdadays), but from those collaborations, I gained contacts of medical practitioners, private clinics, and public hospitals in Vietnam for my future research on digital transformation in healthcare. It would be wise to think carefully about your research identity and agenda, then determine whether participation in a research collaboration, which is less relevant to your research area(s), would contribute to building up those identity and agenda. It should be always beneficial to collaborate in research projects, but keep track of the limited resources that you can spend on these projects as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-what-are-my-roles-in-a-research-collaboration&quot;&gt;3. What are my roles in a research collaboration?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are different stages of a research project that you could get involved in, and it doesn’t always need to be at the beginning of the project. I was asked several times to join a research project as a methodologist, whose tasks mainly concerned with performing statistical analyses on data that had already been collected. In this role, you wouldn’t necessarily need to have an in-depth understanding of the literature of the research, and your main contributions would be to execute rigorous analyses to produce reliable and valid results based on the given data set. Sometimes, I was also involved in interpreting the findings (which would require understanding the research topic to some extent), but most of the times my job finished with writing up the Analysis section (and often the Research Design section as well) of the manuscript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior researchers with extensive experiences in the field would ideally contribute to the Discussion section of the manuscript, where they would add critical interpretations of the findings and propose directions for future research that are in line with the ongoing trends in the field. Perhaps the straightforward way of being involved in a research is writing the Literature Review section, which may include related work, theoretical background, and hypothesis development. This task can be done by any member - it is usually the task of a Research Assistant (note: if you are a research student who wants to collaborate in research, then offer to do this task), or the person who came up with the research idea in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-how-do-i-get-involved-in-a-research-collaboration-especially-with-people-whom-i-havent-worked-with-before&quot;&gt;4. How do I get involved in a research collaboration (especially with people whom I haven’t worked with before)?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways depending on the current stage of your research career. For example, if you are a research student, cold-emailing a prolific professor in your field may not be the best way to initiate a research collaboration (not to mention you may even upset your research supervisor/advisor). You may also present your research at a conference, and someone who likes the presented idea might approach you (or the other way around) and initiate the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way, in my opinion, is to always prepare and offer something tangible to your potential collaborators before asking them to work with you. For instance, have you got a clear idea of the research topic that you want to work on? Most of the times, I prepare the abstract and/or a brief literature review of the research project that I’m working on and show these materials to the potential collaborators, or at least explain the idea and the detailed roadmap for working on the idea, as well as attach some of my publications that are relevant to the proposed idea. The point here is to show the potential collaborators that you know exactly what you are doing/proposing and that the outcome(s) is clear and achievable i.e., your potential collaborators have some confidence that they won’t waste their time and efforts in a fruitless project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also been (quite often) involved in projects where everyone would start brainstorming research ideas in the first few meetings. From my experiences, many of these projects resulted from an “arranged marriage” between different departments, where researchers in different fields are nominated to work together on a multidisciplinary project (with some internal funding) with the aim to build collegiality between the departments. In other occasions, a new project may result from a coffee chat between colleagues who are close friends to each other. I have found the latter to create smoother and more successful collaborations i.e., research papers were published fast and in highly ranked outlets, whereas the former often led to a more bumpy journey - which would not be surprising at all, given the different levels of familiarity you have with your collaborators. It doesn’t mean that collaboration with new people should be avoided (it’s the opposite, if your primary objectives are to learn new things and expand your research network), but (1) it would always be easier if the research idea is clear, and (2) the collaboration is managed properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are the four notes that come from my reflection on being involved in research collaboration. I hope you would find some of these notes useful and let me know in the comments below if you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>[&quot;Duy Dang-Pham&quot;]</name></author><summary type="html">Some personal notes on getting involved in multi-disciplinary research collaboration.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/img/Elsevier-collab-image.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/img/Elsevier-collab-image.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">RMIT Vietnam &amp;amp; Vietnam Airlines - Digital Transformation &amp;amp; Cyber Security Management workshop</title><link href="/2021/09/17/vna-workshop-digital-transformation-cybersecurity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RMIT Vietnam &amp;amp; Vietnam Airlines - Digital Transformation &amp;amp; Cyber Security Management workshop" /><published>2021-09-17T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2021-09-17T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>/2021/09/17/vna-workshop-digital-transformation-cybersecurity</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/09/17/vna-workshop-digital-transformation-cybersecurity.html">&lt;p&gt;The School of Business &amp;amp; Management successfully organised a virtual training workshop for 200 staff from Vietnam Airlines on Friday, September 17, with introductions from Ms. Loan Duong Hong and the Government Affairs team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The School’s Academic Team, led by Professor Mathews Nkhoma included Associate Professor Trung Nguyen, Professor Robert (Bob) McClelland, Dr. Duy Dang, and Dr. Hiep Pham, who provided a workshop on the topic of “Digital Transformation and Cyber Security Management”. Digital transformations are shaping the world and the workplace as we know it, bringing greater interconnectedness among people, organisations, and machines, as well as enhanced speed and agility, but also posing a significant leadership challenge.&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaders in this fast-paced digital era must consider new skills and mindset modifications as they navigate the dynamic challenges of blurred borders, fluid collaborations, and agility pressures. This workshop aimed to help participants grasp important leadership concerns in the digital era and acquire the abilities necessary to lead in a world where digital disruption is the norm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delegates at the event also had the honor of receiving the keynote speeches from Professor Peter Coloe, Chairman of RMIT Vietnam, and Mr. Dang Ngoc Hoa, Chairman of Vietnam Airlines, as well as welcoming the Deans of respective Schools, including Professor Julia Gaimster from SCD and Professor Brett Kirk from SST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/vna-17-Sept-21.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RMIT Vietnam &amp;amp; Vietnam Airlines - Digital Transformation &amp;amp; Cyber Security Management workshop&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;RMIT Vietnam &amp;amp; Vietnam Airlines - Digital Transformation &amp;amp; Cyber Security Management workshop on the 17th of September, 2021&lt;/figcaption&gt;</content><author><name>[&quot;Duy Dang-Pham&quot;]</name></author><summary type="html">The School of Business &amp;amp; Management successfully organised a virtual training workshop for 200 staff from Vietnam Airlines on Friday, September 17, with introductions from Ms. Loan Duong Hong and the Government Affairs team. The School’s Academic Team, led by Professor Mathews Nkhoma included Associate Professor Trung Nguyen, Professor Robert (Bob) McClelland, Dr. Duy Dang, and Dr. Hiep Pham, who provided a workshop on the topic of “Digital Transformation and Cyber Security Management”. Digital transformations are shaping the world and the workplace as we know it, bringing greater interconnectedness among people, organisations, and machines, as well as enhanced speed and agility, but also posing a significant leadership challenge.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/img/vna-17-Sept-21.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/img/vna-17-Sept-21.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Vietnam Chapter of the Association for Information Systems (VAIS) has been established</title><link href="/2021/07/20/vietnam-chapter-of-ais.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vietnam Chapter of the Association for Information Systems (VAIS) has been established" /><published>2021-07-20T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>/2021/07/20/vietnam-chapter-of-ais</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/07/20/vietnam-chapter-of-ais.html">&lt;p&gt;I am glad to announce that the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://communities.aisnet.org/vietnamais/home&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;Vietnam Chapter of the Association for Information Systems (VAIS)&lt;/a&gt;, has been officially established. The goal of the VAIS is to foster collaboration in the research, teaching, and practice of information systems in Vietnam.&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more about this news from RMIT Vietnam News: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rmit.edu.vn/news/all-news/2021/july/new-collaboration-to-boost-research-in-information-systems&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.rmit.edu.vn/news/all-news/2021/july/new-collaboration-to-boost-research-in-information-systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>[&quot;Duy Dang-Pham&quot;]</name></author><summary type="html">I am glad to announce that the new Vietnam Chapter of the Association for Information Systems (VAIS), has been officially established. The goal of the VAIS is to foster collaboration in the research, teaching, and practice of information systems in Vietnam.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/img/blog_9May_1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/img/blog_9May_1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tổng quan về trải nghiệm thuật toán (AX)</title><link href="/2021/07/17/tong-quan-trai-nghiem-thuat-toan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tổng quan về trải nghiệm thuật toán (AX)" /><published>2021-07-17T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2021-07-17T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>/2021/07/17/tong-quan-trai-nghiem-thuat-toan</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/07/17/tong-quan-trai-nghiem-thuat-toan.html">&lt;p&gt;Trí tuệ nhân tạo đang ngày càng trở thành một phần không thể thiếu trong cuộc sống hàng ngày với nhiều hình thức khác nhau: từ hệ thống đề xuất thương mại điện tử đến dịch vụ đề xuất phim, từ dịch vụ tổng hợp nội dung đến hệ thống hướng dẫn lộ trình. Mặc dù việc áp dụng nhanh chóng các công nghệ thuật toán có khả năng cải thiện trải nghiệm của người dùng một cách đáng kể, nhưng việc người dùng chấp nhận những đề xuất này như thế nào vẫn còn là một ẩn số. Nói cách khác, những yếu tố nào sẽ ảnh hưởng đến sự hài lòng của chúng ta khi sử dụng các thuật toán đề xuất này? Và làm thế nào chúng ta có thể cải thiện “trải nghiệm thuật toán” (AX) của người dùng?&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;vấn-đề-của-trí-tuệ-nhân-tạo-ai-từ-góc-nhìn-của-người-dùng&quot;&gt;Vấn đề của trí tuệ nhân tạo (AI) từ góc nhìn của người dùng&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bằng cách phân tích hàng ngàn đánh giá của người dùng trên mạng xã hội bao gồm Facebook, Netflix và Google Maps, Eiband et al. (2019) đã khám phá rằng không chỉ độ chính xác mà sự tương tác giữa người dùng và hệ thống cũng ảnh hưởng đến trải nghiệm của họ. Một mặt, nghiên cứu này cho thấy các vấn đề liên quan đến thuật toán, như sự thiên vị trong hiển thị nội dung (Facebook), sự không phù hợp giữa đề xuất và sở thích của người dùng (Netflix) hoặc điểm đến được gợi ý không chính xác (Google Maps) là những vấn đề phổ biến của các hệ thống này. Mặt khác, người dùng có thể cảm thấy khó chịu khi họ không có quyền kiểm soát cách hệ thống hoạt động. Ví dụ, người dùng có thể cảm thấy khó chịu khi họ muốn đi tuyến đường ven biển trong chuyến du lịch của họ, nhưng Google Maps liên tục chuyển thành tuyến đường cao tốc mà không hề thông báo trước. Ngoài ra, cách các hệ thống phản hồi cho người dùng cũng rất quan trọng. Với hệ thống xếp hạng nhị phân (thích / không thích), người dùng có thể gặp khó khăn để cung cấp phản hồi cho Netflix, và điều này ảnh hưởng đến mức độ phù hợp của các gợi ý phim sau này.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trước những vấn đề này, những nghiên cứu gần đây bắt đầu khám phá khái niệm “trải nghiệm thuật toán” (algorithmic experience – AX) (Alvarado &amp;amp; Waern 2018) – một khái niệm bao quát về tương tác của người dùng với các hệ thống thông minh. Khái niệm này bao gồm nỗ lực thúc đẩy khả năng kiểm soát của người dùng đối với việc ra quyết định của thuật toán, tăng cường nhận thức về cách thức hoạt động của hệ thống, và làm tăng lên hoặc giảm đi tầm ảnh hưởng của thuật toán trong việc ra quyết định.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;trải-nghiệm-thuật-toán-ax-và-khả-năng-kiểm-soát-của-người-dùng&quot;&gt;Trải nghiệm thuật toán (AX) và khả năng kiểm soát của người dùng&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vai trò của con người và khả năng giám sát hệ thống là một trong những chủ đề mới trong lĩnh vực này. Bằng cách cho phép người dùng chứng thực, quản lý và kiểm soát thuật toán, hệ thống có thể khiến người dùng cảm thấy được trao quyền và có khả năng quản lý những gì hệ thống nghĩ về họ (Alvarado &amp;amp; Waern 2018; Kumar et al. 2020). Theo khảo sát, 56% người dùng mong muốn có các tùy chọn để kiểm soát newsfeed của Facebook và tự lọc nội dung, bằng cách bật / tắt / điều chỉnh các chức năng như “People you may know” hay “Marketplace” chẳng hạn (Alvarado &amp;amp; Waern 2018). Cùng quan điểm đó, các nhà nghiên cứu đã đề xuất sự tham gia của con người trong quá trình thiết kế hệ thống AI. Tương tác với người dùng cuối trong quá trình phát triển hệ thống có thể cải thiện nhận thức của họ về sự công bằng và tin cậy của thuật toán, tăng nhận thức và hiểu biết về cách ra quyết định của thuật toán, từ đó có thể dẫn đến sự đồng cảm hơn (Lee et al. 2019).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;trải-nghiệm-thuật-toán-ax-và-tính-minh-bạch&quot;&gt;Trải nghiệm thuật toán (AX) và tính minh bạch&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Những nghiên cứu gần đây đang bắt đầu tập trung vào tác động của sự minh bạch và công bằng của thuật toán lên người dùng, bao gồm cảm nghĩ, mức độ sử dụng, mức độ chấp nhận, sự hài lòng và ý định tiếp tục sử dụng của họ (Shin 2020; Shin, Zhong &amp;amp; Biocca 2020). Trong những nghiên cứu này, tính minh bạch liên quan đến cách hệ thống hiển thị những gì thuật toán biết về người dùng và giải thích lý do tại sao thuật toán lại đưa ra kết quả dựa trên hiểu biết đó (Alvarado &amp;amp; Waern 2018). Từ đó, trải nghiệm thuật toán của người dùng được cải thiện. Đồng quan điểm đó, mô hình vòng lặp phản hồi tin cậy của Shin (2020) cũng cho thấy rằng tính minh bạch và độ chính xác nhận thức sẽ đảm bảo niềm tin đối với thuật toán, từ đó tăng sự hài lòng của người dùng.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;trải-nghiệm-thuật-toán-ax-và-nhận-thức-về-thuật-toán&quot;&gt;Trải nghiệm thuật toán (AX) và nhận thức về thuật toán&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Một nhánh nghiên cứu khác tập trung vào việc giúp người dùng hiểu được các hệ thống thông minh, ví dụ như thông qua các giải thích được trình bày bởi hệ thống. Các giải thích này thường nhắm vào quá trình ra quyết định hoặc một khuyến nghị cụ thể của thuật toán. Một mặt, một số tác giả đồng ý rằng các giải thích ảnh hưởng tích cực đến tính minh bạch (Brunk, Mattern &amp;amp; Riehle 2019). Mặt khác, các nhà nghiên cứu cho rằng hiệu quả của các giải thích phụ thuộc vào các cơ chế minh bạch (bao gồm nhận thức của người dùng, tính đúng đắn, trách nhiệm và khả năng giải thích của thuật toán) cũng như cách hệ thống giải thích (Rader, Cotter &amp;amp; Cho 2018). Ví dụ, sự khác biệt về cách trình bày giải thích, cơ chế và phương thức đưa ra giải thích cũng có ảnh hưởng khác nhau lên nhận thức của người dùng về mức độ công bằng của thuật toán (Binns et al. 2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;kết-luận&quot;&gt;Kết luận…&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Các thuật toán đang trở thành một phần không thể thiếu của hầu hết các dịch vụ hàng ngày, trong đó trải nghiệm thuật toán đang trở thành một chủ đề mới để tiếp cận lĩnh vực “AI con người lấy con người làm trọng tâm”. Nói cách khác, thay vì thúc đẩy mặt kỹ thuật, việc tạo ra AI từ hiểu biết về nhu cầu của con người và xã hội đang được quan tâm hơn cả.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Các nghiên cứu gần đây đã khám phá những cách khác nhau để tăng sự hài lòng và chấp nhận của người dùng đối với AI, bao gồm cải thiện sự tham gia của người dùng, tăng tính minh bạch, sự công bằng hoặc cách sử dụng các giải thích phù hợp. Tuy nhiên, sự hiểu biết của chúng ta về các giải pháp trải nghiệm AI vẫn còn hạn chế. Với hiểu biết về nhận thức của người dùng, có thể sẽ có những công việc trong tương lai tập trung vào thiết kế các trải nghiệm thuật toán, cũng như là chìa khóa để thiết kế các hệ thống lấy con người làm trung tâm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Diem-Trang Vo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edited by Duy Dang-Pham&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alvarado, O &amp;amp; Waern, A 2018, ‘Towards algorithmic experience: Initial efforts for social media contexts’, in Proceedings of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, pp. 1-12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Binns, R, Van Kleek, M, Veale, M, Lyngs, U, Zhao, J &amp;amp; Shadbolt, N 2018, ‘‘It’s Reducing a Human Being to a Percentage’ Perceptions of Justice in Algorithmic Decisions’, in Proceedings of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, pp. 1-14.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brunk, J, Mattern, J &amp;amp; Riehle, DM 2019, ‘Effect of Transparency and Trust on Acceptance of Automatic Online Comment Moderation Systems’, in 2019 IEEE 21st Conference on Business Informatics (CBI), vol. 1, pp. 429-35.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eiband, M, Völkel, ST, Buschek, D, Cook, S &amp;amp; Hussmann, H 2019, ‘When people and algorithms meet: user-reported problems in intelligent everyday applications’, in Proceedings of the 24th International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces, pp. 96-106.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kumar, A, Braud, T, Tarkoma, S &amp;amp; Hui, P 2020, ‘Trustworthy AI in the Age of Pervasive Computing and Big Data’, arXiv preprint arXiv:2002.05657.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lee, MK, Kusbit, D, Kahng, A, Kim, JT, Yuan, X, Chan, A, See, D, Noothigattu, R, Lee, S &amp;amp; Psomas, A 2019, ‘WeBuildAI: Participatory framework for algorithmic governance’, Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction, vol. 3, no. CSCW, pp. 1-35.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rader, E, Cotter, K &amp;amp; Cho, J 2018, ‘Explanations as mechanisms for supporting algorithmic transparency’, in Proceedings of the 2018 CHI conference on human factors in computing systems, pp. 1-13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shin, D 2020, ‘How do users interact with algorithm recommender systems? The interaction of users, algorithms, and performance’, Computers in Human Behavior, p. 106344.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shin, D, Zhong, B &amp;amp; Biocca, FA 2020, ‘Beyond user experience: What constitutes algorithmic experiences?’, International Journal of Information Management, vol. 52, p. 102061.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>[&quot;Duy Dang-Pham&quot;]</name></author><summary type="html">Trí tuệ nhân tạo đang ngày càng trở thành một phần không thể thiếu trong cuộc sống hàng ngày với nhiều hình thức khác nhau: từ hệ thống đề xuất thương mại điện tử đến dịch vụ đề xuất phim, từ dịch vụ tổng hợp nội dung đến hệ thống hướng dẫn lộ trình. Mặc dù việc áp dụng nhanh chóng các công nghệ thuật toán có khả năng cải thiện trải nghiệm của người dùng một cách đáng kể, nhưng việc người dùng chấp nhận những đề xuất này như thế nào vẫn còn là một ẩn số. Nói cách khác, những yếu tố nào sẽ ảnh hưởng đến sự hài lòng của chúng ta khi sử dụng các thuật toán đề xuất này? Và làm thế nào chúng ta có thể cải thiện “trải nghiệm thuật toán” (AX) của người dùng?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/img/blog_9May_1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/img/blog_9May_1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">5 things to do during lockdown</title><link href="/2021/07/14/things-to-do-during-lockdown.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 things to do during lockdown" /><published>2021-07-14T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2021-07-14T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>/2021/07/14/things-to-do-during-lockdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/07/14/things-to-do-during-lockdown.html">&lt;p&gt;As the number of new Covid-19 cases keeps increasing in Ho Chi Minh City (we are having on average 1,000+ new cases every day), my neighborhood entered quarantined mode a few days ago and we are not allowed to leave the house for at least 2 weeks. Here is the list of 5 things one would want to do during a lockdown, to keep life go on as normal as possible, that I want to share with you.&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-keep-your-living-space-clean-and-airy&quot;&gt;1. Keep your living space clean and airy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since you are going to spend 2 weeks (or more) in the same living space, it makes a lot of sense to clean your space regularly. Open windows as much as possible to let in sunlight and fresh air. This will help you feel more comfortable when living in the space, and official health advice sources also recommend ensuring good ventilation in buildings to prevent Covid-19 (see for example https://www.epa.gov/coronavirus/ventilation-and-coronavirus-covid-19).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-eat-healthy-and-be-prepared&quot;&gt;2. Eat healthy and be prepared&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to maintain a healthy diet as much as possible. Don’t eat too much but don’t get too hungry either; eat until you feel full enough. Make sure to eat safe and minimize the risk of getting food poisoning. If delivery is allowed in your area during the lockdown, order some food that can be stored for a long time (you never know if the quarantine might get extended more than 2 weeks). I store plenty of ramens, crackers, and canned food, just in case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-relax-and-do-something-productive&quot;&gt;3. Relax and do something productive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relaxing is necessary to maintain a positive mood, especially for those who have been working hard around the clock before the lockdown happens. At the same time, finding something productive to do makes lockdown less boring. Don’t get me wrong, I believe that productivity should not be the top priority during this tough time, but I found reading books that I haven’t had the time to read or learning a new skill to be as relaxing as watching Netflix and gaming. Ultimately, keep yourself busy with the things that you enjoy doing and try not to let time pass through without doing anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-exercise-indoors&quot;&gt;4. Exercise (indoors)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to run on the treadmill for at least 30 minutes every day. Sometimes I do light weight lifting and cardio exercises indoor. I found exercising during the lockdown period to be good for me both physically and mentally. Make sure to do low-risk exercises and know your pace, so that you won’t hurt yourself. There are many exercises that you can do indoors to stay fit while minimizing physical interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-stay-connected-online-and-follow-the-government-directives&quot;&gt;5. Stay connected (online) and follow the government directives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lockdown stops us from enjoying social activities such as hanging out and seeing each other face-to-face, which can create negative moods. For me, I am fortunate to be in quarantine with my family, so we actually spend more time talking to each other these days than during normalcy. I also socialize with my friends and colleagues online via Facebook and via Teams, and occasionally we share some drinks online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This pandemic creates a challenging time for all of us, and our collective discipline and self-awareness are needed to go back to normalcy. There is a time for everything, and now is the time for us to stay indoors, wear masks, look after our wellbeing, and follow the advice and directives from health experts and the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take care and stay safe everyone!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>[&quot;Duy Dang-Pham&quot;]</name></author><summary type="html">As the number of new Covid-19 cases keeps increasing in Ho Chi Minh City (we are having on average 1,000+ new cases every day), my neighborhood entered quarantined mode a few days ago and we are not allowed to leave the house for at least 2 weeks. Here is the list of 5 things one would want to do during a lockdown, to keep life go on as normal as possible, that I want to share with you.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/img/blog_9May_1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/img/blog_9May_1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>